俄羅斯 莫斯科
隧道追擊的嫌疑犯正從基輔斯基火車站向東逃離
讓他進去
Send him in.
你願意負責這個計畫嗎？
Will you commit to this program?
我做不到
I can't.
把手舉起來
你願意負責這個計畫嗎？
Will you commit to this program?
把手拿出來
你願意負責這個計畫嗎？
Will you commit to this program?
我做不到
I can't.
別開槍
我沒有武器
把無線電給我
別殺我
我跟你並沒有恩怨
諜 影 重 重 3 ： 最 後 通 牒
六周後
中央情報局 蘭利 維吉尼亞州
（愛茲拉•克雷莫 局長，CIA）對你來說沒有哪個地方是安全的
There's no place it won't catch up to you.
每個故事的結局都是這樣
It's how every story ends.
傑森...你註定是一個殺手
It's what you are, Jason, a killer.
永遠都是
You always will be.
開槍啊！快啊！來吧，來吧！
Go ahead. Go on. Go on! Do it! Do it!
她不會讓我這麼做的
She wouldn't want me to.
這是你活下來的唯一理由
That's the only reason you're alive.
“她”是指誰？
Who is "she"?
瑪麗•克魯茲，他的女友
Marie Kreutz, his girlfriend.
在印度被殺了
She was killed in India.
是中情局行動主管沃德•亞伯特下的命令
Director of Operations Ward Abbott arranged it.
也就是說，我們的一位無恥主管殺了他女朋友
So we have a dirty section chief who kills Bourne's girl.
伯恩回來報仇，錄下了亞伯特的供詞
Bourne comes back for revenge, tapes Abbott's confession
然後亞伯特自殺了
and Abbott commits suicide.
而現在他來找我們算帳了
Now Bourne's gunning for us.
這些都是事實
You couldn't make this stuff up.
最近發現伯恩的蹤影是在莫斯科，六個星期前
Bourne's last confirmed location was Moscow, six weeks ago.
是的，長官
Right. Sir.
他在逃亡中，很危險
He's on the run. He's dangerous.
長官，恕我直言，我認為可能還有其他原因
Well, sir, with respect, I think something else could be going on here.
是什麼？他為什麼要逃亡？
What? What's he after?
伯恩去莫斯科是為了找他第一個殺害目標的女兒
The reason Bourne went to Moscow was to see the daughter of his first targ
你的意思是什麼，帕梅？
What's your point, Pam?
可能他在回憶他的過去
Maybe he was retracing his steps.
他在尋找某樣東西，他回憶裡的某樣東西
He's looking for something. Something in his past.
也許他還沒找到，我們需要知道他在找什麼
Maybe he hasn't found it yet and we need to know what it is.
你認為他對我們沒有威脅？
Are you telling me he's not a threat to this agency?
我想如果他真的想害我們，大可以把錄音帶寄到CNN去
I think if he wanted to hurt us, he could have sent the tape to CNN.
也許他會這麼做的
Maybe he still will.
我的首要原則，就是抱著最大的希望做最壞的打算
My number one rule is hope for the best, plan for the worst.
對我而言，伯恩始終是個很大的威脅，除非你能證明我錯了
As far as I'm concerned, Bourne is still a serious threat u
0e:
繼續尋找他的蹤影
Let's keep looking.
是，長官 是，長官
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
義大利 都靈
這是三年前的照片，那時有一半的國際刑警都在追捕他
This one's three years ago. They had half of Interpol after him.
後來他曾出現在那不勒斯，柏林，莫斯科
Turned up in Naples, Berlin, Moscow...
然後又消失無蹤了
Disappeared again.
與他一起逃亡的女子
The girl that he was on the run with.
瑪麗•克魯茲，屍體在地球另一邊的河裡被找到
Marie Kreutz. She was found dead in a river halfway round the world.
頭部中槍
She'd been shot in the head.
這些都意味著什麼？
What connects the dots?
把答錄機關掉
Turn off the tape recorder.
法國 巴黎
我妹妹呢？
Where's my sister?
何不先坐下來？
Why don't you sit down?
她在哪裡？
Where is she?
她死了
She's dead.
是被殺的
She was killed.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我就知道會是這個結果
I knew this could end this way.
我早就知道會是這樣
It was always gonna end this way.
我並不這麼認為
I didn't believe that.
她是怎麼死的？
And how did she die?
被槍殺
She was shot.
當時我們在印度
We were together in India.
那個人的目標是我
He came for me.
你殺了他？
You killed him?
是的
Yes.
現在呢？
And now what?
這些事一定有幕後主使，我要把他找出來
Someone started all of this and I'm gonna find them.
希思羅國際機場，英國 倫敦
喂，是我
Hey. It's me.
是的，他什麼都知道
Yeah. He knows the whole story.
伯恩只不過是冰山一角
Bourne's just the tip of the iceberg.
你聽說過“黑荊棘”計畫嗎？
Have you heard of an Operation Blackbriar?
我要好好整理一下並寫成報導
I'm gonna get my head around this and type it up.
我現在去找你
I'll see you first thing.
好的
Okay.
中情局分局，英國 倫敦
埃施朗電子監測網發現關鍵字“黑荊棘”
Scanning. GoSat 21. I have a hit on ECHELON. Blackbriar.
重複一遍，是“黑荊棘”
I repeat, Blackbriar.
信號似乎來自歐洲
Looks like it's coming from a European signal.
國家安全局，請確認
NSA, please confirm your receipt.
（中央情報局 蘭利 維吉尼亞州）我會找到頻率和座標
I'll bring up the frequency and the coordinates
截獲我們首要的...
...intercept of our principal...
- 長官！ - 什麼情況？
- Sir! - What you got?
我們截獲到了在倫敦的一通電話，內容帶有關鍵字“黑荊棘”
We intercepted a call in London. Keyword, "Blackbriar."
好的，馬上發給紐約
Okay, send it to New York right away.
中情局最高機密反恐，紐約分局
跟蹤到電話來源了？
Track the phone?
登記者是一位叫賽門•羅斯的倫敦記者
Registered to a London reporter named Simon Ross.
為《衛報》工作
Works at the Guardian newspaper.
- 你正在跟蹤他嗎？ - 是的，長官！
- You're tracking him? - Sir. Yeah.
謝謝，麥克
Thanks, Mike.
我們有個調查小組正在跟蹤他
We have a survey team covering him at work
另外還派了一組人潛入他的公寓
and a sneak and peek's on their way to his apartment.
他跟誰聯繫過？他怎麼會知道“黑荊棘”計畫？
Well, who talked to him? How did he find out about Blackbriar?
我不知道，我們已經調查過他的背景
I don't know. We pulled his background
並且反復確認了所有的疑點
and ran a cross-check on any known anomalies.
但什麼也沒有發現，不過我認為只要跟蹤羅斯，就能...
We've come up with nothing. But I think if we follow Ross, we're
0:
雷，羅斯不重要，我們要的是消息來源
Ray, Ross is easy. We want the source.
你聽說過“黑荊棘”計畫嗎？
Have you heard of an Operation Blackbriar?
你有細節嗎？
You have details?
我要好好整理一下並寫成報導
I'm gonna get my head around this and type it up.
我現在去找你
I'll see you first thing.
- 就這些？ - 是的
- Is that all? - Yeah.
我要反恐拘留方案準備好，順便通知殺手待命
I want rendition protocols and put the asset on standby, just in case.
大家聽著，這是4級緊急事件
People, listen up! This is a full priority situation.
吉米，把羅斯的檔案投到1號屏上
Jimmy, give me Ross' profile on one.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
我們的目標是一位元英國記者賽門•羅斯
Our target is a British national, Simon Ross. A reporter.
我要監視他所有的電話記錄，黑莓短訊，公寓，車子
I want all his phones, his BlackBerry, his apartment, his car,
銀行帳戶，信用卡帳戶，旅行記錄
bank accounts, credit cards, travel patterns.
我要在他下一步行動之前，知道他的計畫
I want to know what he's gonna think before he does.
我要知道他的一切秘密
Every dirty little secret he has.
最重要的是，我要知道他線人的名字以及即時位置
And most of all, we want the name and real-time location of his source
這是國家安全局4級緊急事件，有什麼疑問嗎？
This is NSA priority level four. Any questions?
好吧，行動
All right, let's get to it.
賽門•羅斯 國際安全事務通訊員
誰是傑森•伯恩? 特別報導之三
德國BND正與南印度警方聯手調查一位德國女性的死亡原因。該名女性疑為伯恩同夥，在其汽車墮橋之後淹死在河裡。
什麼？
What?
你願意負責這個計畫嗎？
Will you commit to this program?
我做不到
I can't.
收到 威爾遜先生，目標正進入辦公室
Copy that. Mr. Wills, the subject is entering his office.
給我派幾個眼線到街上監視
Give me some eyeballs on the street.
我的現場視頻呢？
Where's my picture, please?
快連上了
Coming online.
連上了
Online now.
吉米，電話線那裡怎麼樣？
Jimmy, how you doing with the phone line?
我們已能監聽他的辦公室電話，現在正在處理手機線路
Yeah, we have an office line. We're working on his cell.
- 還得花多久 - 一個小時，長官
- How long? - An hour, sir.
太慢了
That's too long.
我們怎麼知道他是不是受人指使？
So how do we know he's not spinning for someone?
還有更多黑幕，他很害怕
There was more. He was scared.
- 怕什麼？ - “黑荊棘”計畫
- Scared about what? - Blackbriar.
- 打擾一下，有你的電話 - 是誰打來的？
Sorry. Call for you. ROSS: Who is it?
他不肯說
Won't give his name.
抱歉，失陪一下
Excuse me.
- 在我的線上 - 謝謝
- He's on my line. - Thanks.
賽門•羅斯
Simon Ross.
三號攝像頭，大螢幕
Camera three, screen.
為什麼聽不到對話？
Why aren't we hearing this?
吉米，這是座機，為什麼我們監聽不到？
Jimmy? That's a hard line, Jimmy. Why don't we have it?
我們已經監聽了他的線路，但他不在那條線上，他在用別人的電話
We have his line, sir, but he's not on it. He's u
0n:.,
我看過你的報導
I've been reading your stories.
- 你是誰 - 傑森•伯恩
- Who is this? - This is Jason Bourne.
滑鐵盧車站，南站口，三十分鐘後，獨自過來
Waterloo Station. South entrance. Thirty minutes. Come alone.
特德，儘快搞定聲音信號
Get me audio as soon as you can, Ted.
街道A組、B組
Street teams Alpha, Bravo.
好吧，夥計們，行動，快
Okay, guys, let's work it. Come on.
他去哪裡？
Where's he going?
他開始行動了，派一組眼線到街上監視，行動
Okay, he is on the move. Give me eyeballs on the street. Let's go.
滑鐵盧車站
目標正離開大樓
Subject exiting the building.
所有人注意，找出他的目的地
All right, everyone, let's find out where he's going.
外勤1號，我需要聲音信號
Mobile One, I need audio.
啟動聲音信號
Audio engaged.
外勤1號跟上他，外勤1號跟上他
Mobile One should have him. Mobile One should have him.
外勤1號跟蹤他，聽到內容後通知我
Get Mobile One on it. Let me know when you hear it.
滑鐵盧車站，南站口
Hi. Waterloo Station, south entrance.
- 威爾遜先生 - 他要去哪裡？
Mr. Wills. VOSEN: Where's he going?
目的地是滑鐵盧車站
Destination is Waterloo Station.
很好，滑鐵盧車站
Okay, Waterloo Station.
馬上派眼線前往滑鐵盧車站，派出所有人手
Give me eyes at Waterloo. Put everyone in play.
- 命令殺手行動 - 調動外勤3號
- Let's activate the asset. - Mobilize Tracker Three.
- 到橋上了嗎？ - 還沒有，長官
- Are we at the bridge yet? - Not yet, sir.
好的，外勤3號，叫他們與目標保持距離
Okay, Mobile Three, tell them to stay back.
是
Sir.
請保持監視距離
Please maintain visual contact.
一台預付費手機
Prepaid phone.
給你
Here you go.
外勤1號，請給出目標現在的位置
Mobile One, give me the subject's current location.
收到
Copy that.
長官，目標正在前往滑鐵盧車站的南站口
Sir, the subject is arriving at the south entrance of Waterloo Station.
喂
Hello?
給我傳到5號和7號
Give me that on five and seven as well.
吉米，我需要知道電話的內容
Jimmy, I need that phone.
仔細聽著我要說的話
I want you to listen very carefully to what I'm about to tell you.
到底發生什麼事了？
What the hell's going on?
在你左手邊10點鐘位置，街道對面停著一輛銀色克萊斯勒旅行車
Ten o'clock, to your left, across the street, there's
裡面是一隊監視小組
There's a surveillance team inside.
正前方街道對面，12點位置
Directly across the street, twelve noon,
有個男人在二樓立柱旁
there's a man on the second story, static post.
監視你
He's watching you.
在你左邊50米距離外有個公車站
Now, there's a bus stop 50 meters to your left.
你現在就朝那個方向走去
I want you to walk towards it.
吉米，我需要電話的通話內容！ 昨天就交代了的
Jimmy, I need that phone! I need it yesterday.
他在行動，他在行動
He's on the move. He's on the move.
那不是他的電話，長官
That's not his phone, sir.
再說一遍？
Say again?
那不是他的電話，長官
That's not his phone, sir.
什麼叫不是他的電話？
What do you mean that's not his phone?
那部電話是從哪來的？
Where the hell did he get another phone?
嗯，不，你只要...
Well, no, you just have to...
逮捕隊B組，準備行動
Grab Team B, stand by.
逮捕隊B組，準備就緒
Grab Team B. We're in position.
那裡有一個穿藍色連衣帽的人
All right, there's a man in a blue hooded sweatshirt.
他正在打電話，走到他的身邊，然後停下來
He's talking on a phone. Walk directly to him and stop.
吉米，我們需要通話內容
Jimmy, we need the call. I need that cell phone.
別讓他離開視線範圍
Do not let him get out of sight.
好的，轉過身來
All right, turn around.
那個穿藍色連衣帽的傢伙是誰？
Okay, who's the guy in the blue hood?
他的連絡人嗎？
Is that his contact?
有一輛公車正在靠站，大概10秒鐘後會到達
All right, there's a bus coming. It'll be there in ten seconds.
它一停下來，你就開始往左走
When it stops, I want you to walk directly to your left.
那裡有個天橋，到樓上的賣報小亭那裡去
There's an overpass. Go up the stairs. Stop at the newsstand.
你會在那裡得到進一步指示
You'll get further instructions.
好的，好的
Okay. Okay.
準備行動
Get ready to move.
盯著那輛公交，盯著那輛公交
Watch that bus. Watch that bus.
發生什麼事了？
What? All right, what's going on?
有誰能告訴我狀況，我們失去了一切視頻監控
Somebody tell me. We lost the feed. Grab Team B.
逮捕隊B組，抓住他的連絡人，跟緊羅斯
Intercept the contact and stay with Ross.
嘿！停下！
Hey! Stop!
這裡是外勤1號 目標已開始移動
Mobile One. Target's on the move.
他開始移動了，別跟丟了
Okay, he's on the move. Do not lose Ross.
藍帽子！趴下！馬上！
Blue hood! Down! Now!
走，我們走
Go! Let's go.
哦，該死的
Oh, shit.
這是怎麼回事？
What the hell was that?
長官，我們失去了與外勤1號的聯繫
Sir, we've lost all communication with Mobile One.
右邊！往西，發現目標後通知我們
To the right! Heading west. Let us know when you get a visual!
最後的所在位置是哪裡？
What was the last known position, please?
在通往中央廣場的人行道上，長官
On the walkway, heading towards the concourse, sir.
這裡是監控隊的噩夢，倫敦最忙碌的車站
It's a surveillance nightmare. It's the busiest terminal in London.
接入所有閉路監視系統
Give me all of CCTV's eyes.
正在處理中，長官
On it, sir.
長官，殺手已到現場
Sir, asset's on scene.
你的消息線人是誰？
Who's your source?
他叫什麼名字？ 你的線人是誰？
What's his name? What's your source's name?
聽著，到底發生什麼事了？ 為什麼有一群人在追捕我？
Look, what's going on? Why are these people after me?
因為你知道得太多了
Because you found something.
你與“絆腳石”行動的內部人士溝通過
You talked to someone inside Treadstone.
一個從一開始就參與在其中的人，那個人是誰？
Someone who was there at the beginning. Who is it?
你知道我不能透露
You know I can't tell you that.
你不知道你惹了多大的禍，如果有必要，那些人是會殺人滅口的
You have no idea what you're into here. These people
是因為“黑荊棘”計畫嗎？
Was it Blackbriar? Is that what this is?
什麼“黑荊棘”計畫？
What's Blackbriar?
“絆腳石”計畫的升級版，我的連絡人說一切都是從你開始的
Treadstone upgrade. My source told me it all started wi
他說你是這個骯髒秘密的第一人
He said that you were square one, the dirty little secret.
他說他知道你是誰
He said he knows who you are.
好吧，我們得走了
All right, we have to move.
保持電話聯繫
Answer your phone.
- 就要連上了 - 找到了？
- Coming online. - You got visual?
他到底在哪兒？
Where the hell is he, people?
聽我的指示，現在走向你的右方
Do exactly as I say. I need you to move up to your right.
右手邊第一個電扶梯
First escalator on the right.
馬上系鞋帶，系鞋帶
Tie your shoe. Tie your shoe right now. Tie your shoe.
等著
Wait.
我會從你身邊走過，我要你靠著左手邊的牆走
I'm gonna walk by you. I want you to move along the far wall
4，3，2，1
to your left in four, three, two, one.
起來
Stand up.
很好
That's it.
他在哪兒？
Where the hell is he?
我們絕對不能把他跟丟
We cannot afford to lose this guy, people.
很好，你現在的方向很好，保持那個方向前進
All right, that line you're on is good. Stay on that line. Stay on that line
天啊，那個大塊頭，我想他是他們的人
Oh, the bin man, I think he's one of them.
那個收垃圾的？不是的
The garbage man? Negative.
天啊，他在拿東西
Oh, Jesus. Jesus! He's reaching for something.
- 上帝，他有槍，他有槍 - 保持那個方向
- Oh, God, he's got a gun. - Stay on the line.
他有槍，他有槍
He's got a gun. He's got a gun.
保持那個方向，不要往別處走
Stay on the line you're on. Do not deviate.
找到他了！ 他在那兒，他在那兒
Okay, there he is! Here he goes.
逮捕隊A組，行動
Grab Team A. Go!
他還在跟某人通話
He's still talking to somebody.
他在接受指令，吉米，給我監聽通話內容
He's getting instructions. Jimmy, get me the conversation.
- 外勤2號，我要... - 快，趕快合圍
- Mobile Two, I want... - Come on, lock the box.
趕快合圍，跟進，逮捕隊C組
Lock the box. Move in, Grab Team C.
快點，羅斯，我們得走快點
Hurry, Ross. We gotta move.
混入人群，馬上混入人群
Okay, move through this crowd. Move through this crowd.
馬上隱蔽，混入人群
Get undercover right now. Move through this crowd.
到店裡去
Get in the store.
有人在跟蹤你，到店裡去
There's someone on your tail. Get in the store.
你要從東邊的門出來
You're gonna proceed out the east exit.
在你進門的右手邊
That's to your right as you come into the store.
進入你前方的酒店
Head into the liquor store in front of you.
然後從後門離開，把門鎖上
Go into the back and lock the door.
外勤4號失去聯繫
Mobile Four is down.
那傢伙有幫手，告訴我殺手什麼時候能夠行動
This guy's got help. Tell me when the asset's in the nest.
我需要裡面的信號
Get me a feed in there!
我要逮捕隊C組到裡面去，告訴我那裡發生什麼事了
I want Grab Team C in there. Tell me what's going on.
4號隊移動
Team Four is mobile.
上帝
Jesus Christ.
是傑森•伯恩
That's Jason Bourne.
他在逐一除掉我們的人，你認為他是線人嗎？
He's picking us apart. Do you think he's the source?
一定是他
He's gotta be.
守住所有出口，讓殺手行動
Block all the exits. Give the asset a green light.
把他們兩個都除掉
Take them both out.
待在那別動
Stay there.
我得想辦法突圍出去，你得依我的指示行動
I'm gonna get us out of here. You gotta do exactly what I say.
聽著，這可不是什麼報紙裡瞎編的報導
Listen to me! This isn't some story in a newspaper.
這可是真的，明白嗎？
This is real. You understand me?
好的
Okay.
讓所有特工撤退
Call all agents back.
告訴殺手伯恩的位置：商店後邊
Give Bourne's location at the back of the store to the asset.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
支開所有監控攝像頭
Kill the cameras.
- 伯恩 - 等一下，好像有點不對勁
- Bourne. - Wait. Something's not right.
我從這裡可以看到入口，如果我現在行動，應該能安全逃脫
I can see the entrance from here. If I go now, I can make
伯恩
Bourne?
待在那裡別動
Just stay where you are.
我們不能等了
I don't think we should wait!
有人在朝這個方向走來
I think someone's coming.
我要拼一把
I'm going for it.
不，不，不
No, no, no, no, no!
我們這裡出了些狀況
We have a situation.
請進
Yeah.
克雷莫局長要見你
Director Kramer would like to see you.
我們要得到許可證...
We need to get those warrants...
他說是緊急事件
He said it's urgent.
什麼是“黑荊棘”計畫？
傑森•伯恩
馬德里 西班牙
警方已確認，被害者年齡35歲
What the police will tell me is that they believe the victim is 35-year-old
叫賽門•羅斯，是倫敦的一名著名記者
Simon Ross, a well-known journalist based here in London
供職于《衛報》
with the Guardian newspaper.
現場證據表明他是被槍殺的
It appears that he was gunned down
地點為滑鐵盧車站廣場
right in the middle of the Waterloo Station concourse
時間約為午後3時45分
around 3:45 this afternoon
有上百位乘客目睹了事件的發生
in full view of hundreds of commuters.
這些年，他揭露了許多不為人知的恐怖事件
Over the years, he's uncovered a lot of
unsavory stories about terror
為此，得罪了某些西方國家政府...
that have upset certain Western governments and...
- 嘿，你好 - 在那
- Hi, how are you? - Right over there?
好的
All right.
早上好，先生，您想點些什麼？
Good morning, sir. Can I take your order? Yes.
來個煎蛋，乳酪加胡椒粉，謝謝
I'll have the Heart-Healthy omelet with goat cheese and peppers, please.
- 您想要些什麼，女士？ - 咖啡，謝謝
- Anything for you, ma'am? - Just coffee, please.
只要咖啡？我買單哦
Are you sure? I'm buying.
咖啡就好
I'm good.
局長打來電話，他建議讓你加入行動
So, when the Director called and it was suggested that we bring you on...
建議？真的只是建議而已嗎？
Suggested? You sure it was just a suggestion?
真有意思
You know, it's funny how different things look
從不同角度看事情會有不同想法
depending on where you sit, right?
在我看來，這對你是個幫助，帕梅
I look at this as a favor for you, Pam,
給你個機會完成你未完成的任務
giving you an opportunity to complete some unfinished business.
什麼意思？
Meaning?
伯恩，他在這裡，他是個威脅
Bourne. He's here. He's a threat.
而我們，要的是同樣的東西
And we both want the same thing.
可是我們獲得的手段相去甚遠
But we both go about it in two very different ways.
過去的就讓它過去吧，帕梅
The past is past, Pam. All right?
斯德哥爾摩的事，我們太大意了
We were careless in Stockholm.
那麼滑鐵盧站這次，也是大意嗎？
So what was Waterloo? Just careless again?
有人洩密，這是非常嚴重的國家安全問題
We had a leak. A serious national security situation.
伯恩在我們的監視下現身，我們幾乎沒有時間考慮如何應對
Bourne showed up on our surveillance and we had very littl
一個記者被殺
And a reporter got killed.
伯恩知道我們會行動，關鍵是他來這裡做什麼？
Bourne saw us coming. The question is what was he doing there?
不，關鍵是你怎麼可以
No, the real question is how you managed
讓殺手在公共車站射擊？
to get into a firefight at a public train station.
你和我都知道，危急狀態下不得不做出欠周全的決定
You know as well as I do decisions made in real time are never perf
用不著事後諸葛亮，你這是站著說話不腰疼
Don't second-guess an operation from an armchair.
辦公室見
I'll see you at the office.
好好享用你的蛋白
Enjoy your egg whites.
大家注意了
People!
這位是潘蜜拉•蘭蒂和她的助手湯姆•克羅寧
This is Pamela Landy and her associate, Tom Cronin.
她將領導這次的搜尋行動
She's gonna be quarterbacking the search effort.
報上你們的名字和職務
Say your names. State your specs, please.
一會兒再報名字吧，伯恩的上一個現身地點是哪？
Well, let's do names later, okay? What's Bourne's last fixed position?
倫敦，12:00
London, 1200 Zulu.
狀況呢？他有武器或受傷嗎？
Status. What is he? Armed? Wounded?
他活著，還有行動力
Alive, mobile and unknown.
- 申請跨國追蹤了嗎？ - 是的
- Do we have an ECHELON package? - Yes.
為什麼還未啟動？ 我們在等待
Why isn't it on? We were waiting.
等待？還等什麼？ 什麼... 聽著
Waiting? For what? What... Listen,
你們知道自己面對的是什麼人嗎？
people, do you have any idea who you're dealing with?
這是傑森•伯恩
This is Jason Bourne.
他是你們追蹤過的最難對付的人，而你們已經落後了9小時
You are nine hours behind the toughest target you have ever
我現在要求每個人用上所有注意力，投入百分百精神
Now, I want everyone to sit down, strap in and turn on all you've g
現在立即行動！
That would mean now!
多謝
Thank you.
給我一支隊伍負責籌畫
Give me a team deployment plan.
將羅斯的所有資料放到一號螢幕
I want everything you got on Ross on screen one.
長官，找到線索了
Sir, I think we have something.
我們截獲了羅斯在《衛報》的電郵帳號
We just hacked Ross' e-mail account at the Guardian.
發現昨天前往義大利都靈的來回機票
Found a round-trip ticket to Turin, Italy, yesterday.
08:00到達，12:05起飛
08:00 arrival, 12:05 departure.
我們本可以確定伯恩不是他的線人
I think we can be pretty certain that Bourne's not your source, then.
為什麼？
How?
羅斯剛下都靈飛回倫敦的飛機
Ross's call to his editor where he said he'd just met the source
就打電話給他的編輯，說他剛見過他的線人
took place just after his Turin flight landed.
- 說明他在都靈跟線人會了面 - 那麼？
- He met his source in Turin. - So?
什麼？ 難道伯恩和羅斯先在都靈共進早餐
What? So, what? Bourne met Ross in Turin for breakfast
然後又在同一天約在滑鐵盧車站會面？
and then at noon the same day Bourne calls Ross to demand a meet at Waterloo?
說不定他們還乘坐同一班飛機呢
Maybe they were even on the same flight.
看看都有什麼
Pull up everything you've got.
核對所有CIA內部登記的手機使用情況
Cross-check the secure cell phone usage of everyone with SCI clearance
追查羅斯在都靈的時間內所有打入和打出的電話
against all calls going in and out of Turin, Italy, the morning Ross was
你要找的人是CIA特工，他掌握了高度機密
This guy you're after is a CIA operative with clearance above top secret.
他與羅斯的談話是叛國行為
He's committing treason by talking to Ross.
那麼他既然知道我們
Do you really think while doing that
可以追蹤到他的手機，還會用手機聯絡嗎？
he's gonna use a cell phone that he knows we can track?
未能查到任何記錄
Zero results on the cross-check.
那你有什麼高見？
So, you got any better ideas?
查詢羅斯在都靈整個期間
Yeah, look at all the people whose cell phones were switched off
所有關閉手機的人
the entire period Ross was in Turin.
如果大家都像我一樣經常打電話
I mean, if your people are on their phones as much as mine,
那麼關機的人數應該不多
the list should be pretty small.
三個人：湯姆•布魯斯特，傑克•布林以及尼爾•丹尼爾斯
Three names. Tom Brewster, Jack Boulin and Neal Daniels.
查詢羅斯住處所有與這三個人有關的資料
Okay, now check everything in Ross' apartment against those names.
找共同點
Check for common patterns.
找任何羅斯與人會面的線索
Look for anything that indicates who Ross met.
放大他的單子，放大
Pull up his socials. Pull it up.
看到文件了嗎？
See those documents?
停
Break it.
那是什麼？
Over here. What is that?
就是那裡，名字開頭字母
All right. Right there. Initials.
放大，放到大螢幕上
Pull that up. Bring that up on main.
尼爾•丹尼爾斯
Neal Daniels.
他不是我們在馬德里分站的頭子嗎？
He's station chief in Madrid, isn't he?
是的
Yeah.
通知大使館的安全官
All right, call the RSO at the embassy.
如果丹尼爾斯在那裡，收押他
Have them take Daniels into custody, if he is there.
安娜，派人到卡里諾特街的藏身處
Anna, get grab teams to the Calle Norte safe house.
讓他們全副武裝，告訴他們我們會幫忙封鎖所有入口的
Send them in heavy. Tell them we'll assist with the entry.
全副武裝？丹尼爾斯不是...
Heavy? Daniels isn't really that much of a...
我擔心的是伯恩
I'm worried about Bourne.
如果他不是線人
If he is not the source,
那麼他就是在追蹤這個線人，與我們一樣
then he is after the source, the same as we are.
二隊什麼時候到？
ETA, Team Two.
長官，3分鐘後抵達
Three minutes to destination, sir.
你將拯救美國人民的生命
Your mission will save American lives.
獻身這個計畫
Really give yourself to this program.
我做不到
I can't.
你能做到
You can.
長官，他們已經到達正門
Sir, they're at the front door.
- 5秒鐘 - 即時監控
- Five seconds. - Put it up live.
已經進入
We're in.
警報器被毀壞
The alarm's down.
一定是伯恩
That's gotta be Bourne.
- 保險箱空了 - 靠
- The safe is empty. - Shit.
貌似他匆忙離開的
Looks like he left in a hurry.
監控丹尼爾斯的護照
Track Daniels' passports.
行動
Stand by.
哈蒙德
Hammond.
該死的！派後援部隊！
God damn it! Get a backup team in there!
給我派上後衛隊，立即派上另一隊
Get me a secure line in there. Get the second team over there now!
你來這兒做什麼？
What are you doing here?
柏林行動之後，我就被派到這裡
I was posted here after Berlin.
丹尼爾斯在哪？
Where's Daniels?
他在哪？
Where is he?
喂？
Hello?
哪位？
Who is this?
我是妮可•帕森
This is Nicky Parsons.
她是“絆腳石”計畫的後勤
She was Treadstone. Logistics.
在柏林追捕伯恩時，她也在
She was with us when we hunted Bourne in Berlin.
妮可，我需要進行身份核對
Nicky, I need to do an ID challenge.
代號是麻雀
Code in, Sparrow.
危險回應：紅寶石
回應是珠穆朗瑪峰
Response, Everest.
正常回應：珠穆朗瑪峰
妮可，我是諾亞•沃森，你到現場多久了？
Nicky, this is Noah Vosen. How long have you been on-site?
我剛進來
I just walked in.
在現場有我們兩名同伴，你看到他們了嗎？
We have two officers on-site. Are you in contact with them?
他們被放倒了，不省人事，不過還活著
They're down. Unconscious but alive.
見到尼爾•丹尼爾斯嗎？
Any sign of Neal Daniels?
沒有
No.
妮可，我是帕梅•蘭蒂
Nicky, this is Pam Landy.
我們有理由相信
We have reason to believe there's a connection between
尼爾•丹尼爾斯與傑森•伯恩有關聯
Neal Daniels and Jason Bourne.
伯恩？你仍在找伯恩？我以為那個行動已經終結了
Bourne? You're still looking for Bourne? I thought that case was close
不，有人堅信他仍然是個威脅
No, some people are convinced he's still a threat.
我不這麼認為，不過我必須與他談談，才能知道真相
I disagree, but to find out I need to talk to him.
等一下，妮可
Hold on, Nicky.
- 你這是在幹什麼？ - 我想給他傳達一個資訊
- What the hell are you doing? - I'm trying to send him a message.
你認為伯恩不是威脅？ 他剛又放倒兩個我的人
You don't think Bourne is a threat? He just took out two more of my men.
唯一妥善解決這件事的方法
The only way this has a happy ending, Noah,
就是把他活捉
is if we bring him in alive.
他在追蹤丹尼爾斯
He is going after Daniels.
他想復仇，帕梅，結束這一切的唯一辦法
He wants revenge, Pam, and the only realistic way
就是解除威脅
to end this is to eliminate the threat.
後援什麼時候能到？
How long until backup?
妮可，請你留在原地，保護現場
Nicky, I need you to stay put and secure the premises.
後援將在一小時之後到達，明白嗎？
Backup will be arriving in approximately one hour. Do you copy?
收到，長官
Copy, sir.
我有多長時間？
How long do I have?
3分鐘
Three minutes.
我的車在外面
My car's outside.
我知道丹尼爾斯在哪兒
I know where Daniels is.
這裡是卡里諾特街334號，剛聽到搶響，有人喊叫，應該是美國人
快
Come on.
2分鐘後抵達，長官
Two minutes to destination, sir.
逮捕隊A組和B組...
Grab Teams A and B...
丹尼爾斯在哪兒？
Where was Daniels headed?
今早8點，他電匯了100,000美元到坦吉爾的一個銀行帳戶
At 8:00 this morning, he wired $100,000 to a bank account in Tang
離這裡300英里，如果加快速度 我們能趕得上早班輪船
Right, that's 300 miles away. If we hurry, we can make the morning
你的車停在哪？
Where are you parked?
右邊，離北街20米
To the right, 20 meters, north side of the street.
他們來了
They're coming.
繼續走
Keep moving.
兩個目標從藏身處出來
Two subjects seen exiting safe house.
這是怎麼回事？
What the hell is this?
不，不，等等
Wait, wait, wait! No, no, no!
到底怎麼回事？
What the hell just happened?
目標行蹤丟失，長官
We've lost visual contact with the subjects, sir.
天哪
Christ!
下達指示，對伯恩格殺勿論，即刻生效
Issue a standing kill order on Jason Bourne, effective immediately.
聯繫西班牙方面
Send out a system one alert to all Spanish contacts.
進行全面封鎖
I want all air and ground border exits locked down.
怎麼回事？
What's going on?
丹尼爾斯手上到底有什麼？
What's Daniels got?
“黑荊棘”計畫又是什麼？
What's Operation Blackbriar?
是你自己告訴我，還是我打電話問克雷莫？
Do you want to tell me, or should I call Kramer and ask him?
老天哪，帕梅，這可是在行動中
For Christ's sake, Pam, we're in the middle of an operation.
胡說八道
Bullshit.
你要傑森•伯恩？
You want Jason Bourne,
跟我說實話
level with me.
“黑荊棘”計畫一開始是監視計畫
Operation Blackbriar started as an NEAT surveillance program.
那麼現在是什麼？
And what is it now?
現在它是作為保護傘，掩護我們所有幕後行動
It is now the umbrella program for all our black ops.
包括侵入，押送，試驗性審問
Full envelope intrusion, rendition, experimental interrogation
全部由這個辦公室發出指令
is all run out of this office.
我們是金字塔的頂端，帕梅
We are the sharp end of the stick now, Pam.
包括殺害行動？
Lethal action?
在必要的時候，是的
If we have to, sure.
正因如此，我們才特別，無需許可證
That's what makes us special. No more red tape.
再不用為了等華盛頓簽署命令，眼睜睜看著壞蛋從眼前逃走
No more getting the bad guys caught in our sights,then wat
拜託
Oh, come on.
帕梅，你大場面見過不少，你知道他們有多麼危險
You've seen the raw intel, Pam. You know how real the danger is.
我們需要這樣的行動
We need these programs now.
丹尼爾斯跟這個有什麼關係？
What's the connection to Daniels?
我們在南歐以及北非的所有行動都由他負責
He ran all of our operations in Southern Europe and North Africa,
他掌握著所有資料
so he has everything.
名字，日期，我們在海外的連絡人
Names, dates, ghost sites, who's cooperating with us abroad.
每一個行動
Every operation.
你想讓這些落入伯恩手中，然後流入市場嗎？
You want that stuff in Bourne's hands, out on the market to the highest bidd
應該不會吧
I don't think so.
伯恩不是為了錢，他為了某個原因要找丹尼爾斯
Bourne's not after money. He's after Daniels for a reason.
嗯，管他伯恩想找什麼呢
Well, what does it matter what Bourne is after?
相信我，只要找到丹尼爾斯，我們就能找到他
When we find Daniels, and, believe me, we'll find him,
如果你說得沒錯
if you're right,
伯恩也會在我們手上
we get Bourne, too.
你為什麼要回來？
Why did you come back?
你為什麼要找丹尼爾斯？
Why are you looking for Daniels?
你知道這個是誰嗎？
Do you know who that is?
這個是丹尼爾斯
That's Daniels.
我不知道另外一個是誰，他是誰？
I don't know who that is. Who is he?
他一開始就在場
He was there at the beginning.
我記得自己見過他
I remember meeting him.
第一天
The first day.
丹尼爾斯帶我去見他
Daniels brought me to him.
就是從那裡開始的
That's where it all started for me.
在我身上發生了一些事，我需要知道是什麼
Something happened to me and I need to know what it was
否則我永遠無法擺脫
or I'll never be free of this.
丹尼爾斯說，對你的訓練是試驗性質的
Daniels said the training was experimental.
行為修正
Behavior modification.
必須先讓特工瓦解，然後他們才能負責行動
They had to break down the agents before they became operational.
他說你是第一個
He said you were the first one.
你為什麼要幫我？
Why are you helping me?
當時我跟你合作得非常辛苦
It was difficult for me ... with you.
你真的什麼也不記得了？
You really don't remember anything.
不記得
No.
我們得走了
We have to move.
尼爾•丹尼爾斯護照追蹤，鎖定
長官，威爾遜先生 你應該看看這個
Sir? Mr. Wills? You're gonna want to look at this.
他在坦吉爾
He's in Tangier.
諾亞•沃森
Noah Vosen.
我們找到丹尼爾斯了
We have found Daniels.
他們查到了他在坦吉爾的一個旅館裡，用了他的護照
They've just tracked Daniels' passport to a hotel in Tangier.
他們藉故拖延丹尼爾斯的銀行轉帳
They're holding up a bank transfer he made to keep him in place
同時從卡薩布蘭卡派出了殺手
while they bring an asset up from Casablanca.
他們要幹掉他
They're gonna take him out.
什麼事？
Yeah.
潘蜜拉•蘭蒂，她說有緊急情況
It's Pam Landy. She says it's urgent.
告訴她我沒空
Tell her I'm unavailable.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
摩洛哥 坦吉爾
長官，殺手已經到達機場
Sir, asset has arrived at the airport.
告訴我目標位置
Give me the subject's location.
目標走進莫拉博斯旅館
Subject is now on foot and entering Hotel Velasquez.
旅館距離銀行2.2公里
Hotel is 2.2 kilometers from the bank.
給出旅館正面圖，平面圖，一間間找
All right, get an elevation and a floor plan, tic-tac-toe.
找出房間位置
Locate the room.
告訴殺手房間位置
Give the asset subject location
以及旅館到銀行的路線圖
and the route between the subject's hotel and the bank.
房間位置確定了嗎？
Do we have that room yet?
是的，長官，117號房間
Yes, sir. It's room 117.
掌握旅館匯流排
All right, get a hold of the hotel trunk line.
監控旅館117號房間.
Run all calls through here with an ISO on room 117.
他的位置被防火牆阻擋
His location's being blocked by the firewall.
不，他們已經找到丹尼爾斯了，也知道他在哪兒
No, they found Daniels. They know where he is.
他們派出殺手去解決他
They'll get one of the operatives to terminate him.
把殺手找出來
Find out who.
戴仕
Desh.
告訴他你要見他，說你要給他一部新手機
Tell him you're gonna meet him and you have a new phone for him.
如果你阻止了戴仕，他們也會找別人的
If you stop Desh, they'll just get someone else.
我們不是要阻止他，而是要跟蹤他
No, we're not gonna stop him, we're gonna follow him.
他會帶領我們找到丹尼爾斯
He'll take us right to Daniels.
長官，殺手背離了預定路線
Sir, the asset is deviating off course.
讓他去
Let it play.
殺手意外停止行動
Asset unscheduled stop.
長官，殺手正在向目標移動
Sir, asset is on the move en route to subject.
長官，有人未經授權
Sir, we have an unauthorized breach.
侵入我們的網路
Someone with active system knowledge penetrated our protocol.
在當地時間14:11向殺手發送指令
Instructions were sent to the asset at 1411 local time.
指令是有效的
Trace is confirmed and valid.
是通過妮可•帕森註冊的電腦
It came from a computer belonging to Nicky Parsons.
背離發生在哪個地點？
Where did the course deviation occur?
貝爾基路南面，過了佛郎路
South to Rue de Belgique, stationary Place de France.
帕森就在那
That's where Parsons is.
解決丹尼爾斯之後，讓殺手解決妮可
When we're finished with Daniels, send the asset after her.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
找到帕森，找到伯恩
We find Parsons, we find Bourne.
諾亞，你這是幹什麼？
Noah, what are you doing?
- 現在不是時候 - 我需要知道，到底是怎麼回事
- Not now. - I wanna know what's going on.
我說了現在不是時候
I said not now!
你依據什麼發佈這個指令？
What basis are you continuing this operation on?
我的依據就是妮可已經危及我們的隱蔽行動
On the basis that Nicky Parsons has compromised a covert operation.
她把我們置於不利境地
She is up to her neck in this!
這個行動是針對丹尼爾斯的，不是妮可
This is about Daniels, not Nicky!
她背叛了我們
She has betrayed us.
你根本不知道情況，諾亞
You don't know the circumstances, Noah.
天哪，她現在跟伯恩一條戰線
She's in league with Jason Bourne, for Christ's sakes!
你無權殺死她
You do not have the authority to kill her!
哦，我有權，你最好識點時務
Oh, yes, I do. And you had better get on board.
諾亞，她是我們的人
Noah, she's one of us.
你一旦走出這一步，將要如何收場？
You start down this path, where does it end?
我們獲勝的時候就是收場的時候
It ends when we've won.
解決丹尼爾斯之後，讓殺手幹掉他倆
When we're finished with Daniels, send the asset after them.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
- 好了，快點 - 行動
- Okay, come on. - Stand by...
2分鐘，長官，2分鐘
Two minutes, sir. Two minutes.
告訴銀行解除電匯凍結
Tell the bank to release the funds.
你好
Hello?
錢已經到戶
他正離開
He's on the move.
他已經到位
On it, sir.
200米
Two hundred meters.
快點，我應該多準備點跟蹤攝像頭
Okay, come on, I want to lay in some preliminary tracking.
停車
Stop!
發密信，就說我們死了
Code it in. We need to be dead.
先生，殺手證實兩個目標都已經被消滅
Sir? Asset confirms both targets are down.
活要見人，死要見屍
I want to be sure about this.
讓拉巴特的站長確認死亡
Ask the station chief from Rabat to confirm the deaths
秘密搜尋屍首
and do a sub-rosa collection of the bodies.
我要求這件事萬無一失
I want to tie this thing off completely.
小心監視蘭蒂
And keep an eye on Landy.
什麼事？
Yeah?
伯恩和妮可•帕森都死了
Bourne and Nicky Parsons are dead.
你確定嗎？
You sure about that?
拉巴特的站長正在核實
Our station chief in Rabat is confirming.
絕對不能讓我暴露
I can't afford to have this come back to me.
不用擔心，你不會有事的
Don't worry. You're protected.
一定記住我們派蘭蒂到你那裡的原因
Just remember why we put Landy there.
如果“黑荊棘”計畫洩露
If Blackbriar goes south,
我們就把責任推給她，重新開始
we'll roll it up, hang it around her neck and start over.
我能看到他們的臉
I can see their faces.
我殺過的每一個人
Everyone I ever killed.
只是不知道他們的名字
I just don't know their names.
瑪麗過去常常...
Marie used to try to
...幫助我回憶他們的名字
help me remember the names.
“任務中止”
目標：尼瓦納•瓦博斯，國籍：尼日利亞，執行人：傑森•伯恩，“絆腳石計畫”， 結果：失敗
我想為我做過的…
I've tried to apologize for...
做過的一切道歉
For what I've done.
為我現在做的事情道歉
For what I am.
但是我的心依然沉重
None of it makes it any better.
他們會繼續追殺你
They're gonna come for you again.
你必須從此逃亡
You're gonna have to run now.
“絆腳石”計畫，傑森•伯恩
實驗物件表現出反抗跡象
阿爾伯特•赫斯醫生授權…
阿爾伯特•赫斯醫生，職位：首席醫務官
對象在99年6月1日被送到紐約，東71街415號“絆腳石”特別治療部門
特別研究部指導訓練官，尼爾•丹尼爾斯記錄
我們該出發了
We should go.
事情會好起來的
It gets easier.
丹尼爾斯先生的東西都在這兒
所有的嗎？
是的
打開看看
中央情報局 紐約40街105號
紐約
情報站站長奧瑪巴剛打電話過來
Station chief in Rabat just called.
他們找到了屍體
They found a body.
- 伯恩？ - 戴仕
- Bourne? - Desh.
帕梅，你應該看看這個
Pam. You need to see this.
一個叫吉爾波特•皮安特的人剛入境
A passport for Gilberto de Piento just cleared immigration.
這是“絆腳石”計畫中，傑森•伯恩的化名之一
It's an early Treadstone identity registered to Jason Bourne,
他從來沒有使用過這個化名，這個化名也從來沒有出現過
but he never used it, and it never went to the grid.
伯恩還活著
Bourne's alive.
他們不知道嗎？
They don't know?
如果知道，他們現在就不會呆在這裡
Well, if they knew, Vosen wouldn't be in his office right now.
他真是冒了極大風險
It's a hell of a risk.
也許伯恩就是想讓我們知道
Maybe Bourne wants us to know.
就像上次在那不勒斯一樣，也許他在和我們聯繫
Just like Naples. Maybe he's communicating.
也許他在聯繫你
Maybe he's trying to communicate with you.
那麼我們應該回復
Then we should communicate back.
我想我知道伯恩在尋找什麼
I think I know what Bourne's looking for.
吉爾波特•皮安特 吉爾波特•皮安特
Gilberto de Piento. Gilberto de Piento.
你的夥伴在等你
Your party is waiting for you.
潘蜜拉•蘭蒂
Pamela Landy.
我聽說你還在找我
I hear you're still looking for me.
伯恩？
Bourne?
你想怎麼樣？
What do you want?
什麼事？
Yeah?
你最好過來，我們發現了新情況
Better get in here. We got a situation.
我…
I...
我想...謝謝你提供的錄音帶
I wanted to thank you for the tape.
事情已經全部解決了
It's all tied off. It's over.
我想我應該對你道歉
I guess I owe you an apology.
是官方的嗎？
Is that official?
不，非官方的，你知道原委的
No. Off the record. You know how it is.
追蹤結果？
You tracing this?
還要50秒
Fifty seconds to trace.
- 再見 - 等等
- Goodbye. - Wait. Wait.
大衛•韋伯，是你的真名
David Webb. That's your real name.
你生於1971年4月15日，在密蘇里州的涅克薩
You were born 4/15/71 in Nixa, Missouri.
為什麼不過來 我們好好談談？
Why don't you come in and we'll talk about it?
這裡面絕對有問題
Something is very wrong here.
伯恩？
Bourne?
好好休息一下，帕梅
Get some rest, Pam.
你看起來很疲倦
You look tired.
他在看著她
He's looking right at her.
大家聽好
People, listen up!
這是國家安全的緊急情況
This is a national security emergency.
我們即將受到嚴重威脅
We have an imminent threat.
我要出去
I'm going out there.
我現身，他就會找到我
If I show myself, he'll find me.
傑森•伯恩還活著，就在紐約
Jason Bourne is alive and is at large in New York City,
相信就在我們周圍方圓1000碼
and, we believe, within 1,000 yards of this building.
我要求馬上封閉周圍12個街區
I want an immediate 12-block lockdown of the area.
馬上通知蘭利總部
Send a flash message to Langley.
啟動本地後備系統
Prep for local backup assistance.
蘭蒂剛離開大樓
Landy just left the building!
竊聽她的電話
Stay with her phone.
她正在用手機收短信
She's using her cell. There's an incoming text.
- 我要短信內容 - 正在獲取，先生
- Get it. - Working on it, sir.
我們有幾個人跟蹤蘭蒂？
How many do we have on Landy?
6個，還有後援正在到達
Six men. More on the way.
我收到了，先生，現在就顯示到螢幕上
I've got it, sir! Coming up on the screen now.
都鐸城路和42街 10分鐘後，單獨見面
跟蹤蘭蒂的所有人，馬上去都鐸城路
Anybody not on Landy goes directly to Tudor City.
準備車輛，我們上車指揮
Get the vehicles. We're going mobile.
- 第二組，第二組 - 所有小組集合
- Team Two. Team Two. - All teams, call in.
178號
178th.
那是一個死胡同，他為什麼要這麼做？
There's only one way out of there. Why would he do that?
他在困住自己
He's trapping himself.
不是一個會面的好地點，太顯眼了
It's a bad place to meet. It's too exposed.
他選這個地方一定有他的理由
He wouldn't have chosen it if he didn't have a reason.
目標還在行進
Subject is en route.
屋頂43，看到目標通知我們
Roof 43, let me know when you have visual.
屋頂43，隨時待命
Roof 43, standing by.
待命
Standing by.
好，我們現在行動，覆蓋周圍200米
Okay, folks, here we go. Box 200 meters.
已就位
Visual on leader.
地面43號就位
43 ground in position.
你們一看到蘭蒂，馬上通知我
As soon as you have eyes on Landy, I wanna know.
好，她來了
Okay, here we go.
收到，我也看到她了
Copy that. I see her.
有伯恩的跡象嗎？
Any sign of Bourne?
沒有
Negative.
沒有發現目標
No sign of target.
諾亞•沃森
Noah Vosen.
我是傑森•伯恩
This is Jason Bourne.
我還在想你什麼時候能給我打電話
I was wondering when you were going to make this call.
你怎麼得到這個號碼的？
How did you get this number?
你不會真以為我去都鐸城路吧
You didn't actually think I was coming to Tudor City, did you?
我沒這麼想
No, I guess not.
但是如果你想跟我談
But if it's me you want to talk to,
也許我們可以安排一個會面地點
perhaps we can arrange a meet.
你現在在哪？
Where are you now?
我在我的辦公室
I'm sitting in my office.
我不信
I doubt that.
你為什麼不信？
And why would you doubt that?
如果你現在就在辦公室
If you were in your office right now,
那麼我們就是在面對面談話
we'd be having this conversation face to face.
諾亞•沃森
Noah Vosen.
密碼10取消行動
This is a code ten abort.
所有人回到車上，密碼10取消行動
I want everyone back in the vehicles. This is a code ten abort.
快走！快走！
Let's go! Let's go!
絕密：黑荊棘計畫
“絆腳石”計畫升級到“黑荊棘”計畫
被清除的美國公民
什麼事？
Yeah?
威爾森，馬上檢查我的辦公室
Wills, check my office.
見鬼！
Damn it!
怎麼回事？
What's going on?
讓保安到這來
We need building security up here.
- 他拿走了全部檔案 - 媽的！
- He's got everything. - God damn it!
封鎖大樓周圍4個街區
All right, set a four-block perimeter around the building.
我們要發現目標
Somebody give me a visual.
我要求整座大樓都被搜查
I want the entire building searched.
每個房間，每個走廊，每個壁櫥，每個通風道
Every room, every hallway, every closet, every goddamn air duct.
明白嗎？我要你們找到他！
You understand? I want him found!
發生什麼事了？
What just happened?
伯恩進入大樓，打開了沃森的保險櫃
Bourne just broke into CRI. He got into Vosen's safe.
去哪兒？
Where to?
東71街415號
415 East 71st Street.
71街415號？天啊，帕梅
Four-fifteen-seventy-one? Jesus, Pam.
發現目標
Target in sight.
目標向北轉入第8大道
North on Eighth.
目標進入港務局
He's headed east in the Port Authority.
授權所有特工，可以格殺勿論
All agents have shoot-on-sight authorization.
在那！
Right there!
- 先生，他開下房頂了 - 什麼？
- Sir, he drove off the roof. - What?
他開下房頂了！
He drove off the roof!
他下車了，現在在跑
He's on foot. He's running.
員警！不許動！
Police! Freeze!
舉起手來！
Put your hands in the air!
叫後援！
Call for backup!
先生，你看伯恩的生日，先生
Sir, sir, take a look at this! Bourne's birthday, sir.
- 有什麼問題？ - 請看，先生
- What about it? - Check that out.
蘭蒂告訴伯恩他的生日是71年4月15號
Sir, Landy told Bourne that his birthday was 4l15l71.
她告訴他的是一個密碼
Oh, my God. It's a code.
都停下手頭的工作！聽著！
Everything stops. Everything stops! Listen up!
4/15/71，新的任務
4l15l71. New assignment, numbers.
這組數字是什麼意思？快解碼！
What does it mean? Give me encryption codes!
先生，轉換成經緯度
Sir, if you plug them in as variables of longitude and latitude
就是喀麥隆
you get Cameroon.
41571是肯塔基州瓦爾尼的郵遞區號
41571 is the zip code for Varney, Kentucky.
她給的是什麼數字？
What date did she give him?
4/15/71
4/15/71.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
這組號碼表示東71街415號
SRD is at 415 East 71st Street.
她告訴了他訓練中心的地址
She just gave him the training facility.
哦，天啊
Oh, Christ.
所有小組跟著我
Bring all the teams in behind us.
快！報警！
Hurry up! Somebody call 911!
救救他！
Help him!
先生，特工沒有殺掉伯恩，我們也跟丟了
The asset lost Bourne. We lost him.
阿爾伯特，我是沃森
Hello? Albert, it's Vosen.
伯恩知道了一切，他正在去你那兒
Bourne knows everything and he's on his way to you right now.
他要回家了
He's coming home, Noah.
我還有多長時間？
How long do I have?
我不知道
I don't know.
你趕快跑吧
Just get the hell out of there.
不，我要留下
No, I'm gonna stay.
他會來訓練中心一側，那是他以前待過的地方
He'll head for the training wing. That's what he knows.
我會穩住他，直到你趕來
I'll keep him in play till you get there.
你給了我這些，他們會殺了你
They'll kill you for giving me this.
4/15/71也不算密碼
4l15l71 isn't much of a code.
我猜沃森已經趕過來了
My guess is Vosen is on his way already.
你為什麼這麼做？
Why'd you do it?
因為那不是我的工作
Because this isn't what I signed up for,
他們對你做了這些，“黑荊棘”計畫
what they did to you, Blackbriar.
不是我們
This isn't us.
那麼你就做點什麼吧，你需要的都在裡面
Then do something about it. Everything you need is in there.
所有一切
Everything.
大衛，何不和我一起進去？
David. Why don't you come in with me?
我們一起去會更好
It'll be better if we do this together.
不
No.
這裡是我開始的地方
This is where it started for me.
也是結束的地方
This is where it ends.
是蘭蒂
That's Landy.
Mandy Aaron, dial extension 200, please.
Mandy Aaron, dial extension 200.
封鎖這座大樓
All right, lock this building down.
周圍1個街區警戒
Set a secure perimeter of one block.
你好，我是潘蜜拉•蘭蒂，我要發送機密文件
Hello. This is Pamela Landy. I have to send a classified document.
派一個小組去追伯恩
Get a team to SRD after Bourne.
其他人派到這個醫院的所有公共區域
And put someone in every public area of this hospital.
電梯間，員工電梯，快！
Okay. Elevator shafts, service entrances, go!
見鬼！南邊的電梯，快！
Damn it! South bay! Go!
先生們，這是緊急情況
Gentlemen, this is a priority one situation!
要求你們的完全合作
You will give us your full cooperation.
給我看過去3分鐘大廈的全部監視錄影
Give me playback for the entire building for the last three minutes.
是的，顯示
Yes, sir.
快！快！
Move! Move!
這個！這是哪裡？
This one, here! Where is this?
一樓
First floor.
我自己去抓蘭蒂
I'll take Landy on my own.
你最好找個好律師
You better get yourself a good lawyer.
美國處於危險的剃刀邊緣
A republic lives on the knife's edge.
我們完成後，你就不再是大衛•韋伯
When we are finished with you, you will no longer be David Webb.
你甚至記不得那個名字是誰
You may not even remember who he was.
你知道為什麼我們這麼對待你嗎？
You know why we're treating you like this?
你好，傑森
Hello, Jason.
我相信你是遇到了一些問題
I believe you've been having some problems.
把槍放下
Put the gun down.
如果我不想談的話就不會到這來了
I wouldn't be here if I didn't want to talk.
我過去三年一直在逃亡
I've spent three years running.
三年來一直想知道自己是誰
Three years trying to find out who I am.
你還是記不起來，對吧？
You've still not got it all back, have you?
破碎的記憶難以拼湊
Still not filled in the pieces.
一直都是你
It was always you.
我沒有武器，傑森
I'm unarmed, Jason.
為什麼是我？你為什麼要選我？
Why me? Why did you pick me?
你真的記不起來，是不是？
Your really don't remember, do you?
不是我們選擇你，而是你選擇了我們
We didn't pick you. You picked us.
你是自願的
You volunteered.
就在這裡
Right here.
即使我們已經警告了你
Even after you were warned.
韋伯上尉
Captain Webb.
早上好，上尉
Good morning, Captain.
你來到這
You came in here.
眼睛都沒眨，傑森
You didn't even blink, Jason.
你把這個遞給了我
You just handed me these.
大衛•韋伯
所有的事情都對你解釋了嗎？
Has everything been explained to you?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
你說你想報效國家
You said you wanted to serve.
你的任務會拯救美國公民的生命
Your missions will save American lives.
我知道，先生
I understand, sir.
你說過我會拯救美國公民的生命
You said I'd be saving American lives.
你確實是這樣
You were.
我是在替你殺人
I was killing for you.
替他們殺人
For them.
你完全知道你選擇留下，意味著什麼
You knew exactly what it meant for you if you chose to stay.
我們完成後，你就不再是大衛•韋伯
When we are finished with you, you will no longer be David Webb.
你讓我成為誰，我就成為誰，先生
I'll be whoever you need me to be, sir.
你不能逃避你做過的事，傑森
You can't outrun what you did, Jason.
你讓自己成為了後來的你
You made yourself into who you are.
最終你必須面對現實
Eventually you're gonna have to face the fact
是你在這裡選擇成為了傑森•伯恩
you chose right here to become Jason Bourne.
你很久沒有睡覺了
You haven't slept for a long time.
你決定了嗎？
Have you made a decision?
這樣沒法繼續
This can't go on.
你必須現在決定
You have to decide.
他是誰？
Who is he?
我們已經討論過了
We've been through that.
他做了什麼？
What did he do?
那並不重要
It doesn't matter.
你找到我們
You came to us.
你是自願的
You volunteered.
你說你會做任何事
You said you'd do anything it takes to
來拯救美國公民的生命
save American lives.
你不是在說謊，對不對？
You're not a liar, are you?
或者太軟弱
Or too weak
不能勝任？
to see this through?
就這樣
This is it.
忘掉大衛•韋伯
Let go of David Webb.
獻身這個計畫
Really give yourself to this program.
你不再是
You're no longer
大衛•韋伯
David Webb.
從現在起，你就是傑森•伯恩
From now on, you'll be known as Jason Bourne.
歡迎加入這個計畫
Welcome to the program.
你現在記起來了？
Do you remember now?
我記起來了
I remember.
我記起來一切
I remember everything.
我再也不是傑森•伯恩
I'm no longer Jason Bourne.
那麼你會殺我嗎
So now you're gonna kill me.
不
No.
你根本不配掛在蘭利牆上的星星
You don't deserve the star they'd give you on the wall at Langley.
他去屋頂了！
He's headed for the roof!
你為什麼沒有開槍？
Why didn't you take the shot?
你知道為什麼要殺我嗎？
Do you even know why you're supposed to kill me?
看看我們自己
Look at us.
看看他們讓你付出的是什麼
Look at what they make you give.
早上好，參議員們
Good morning, senators.
請允許我先發表一個聲明
If I may, I'd like to begin by making a statement for the record.
檔顯示愛茲拉•克雷莫授權6項非法的…
The file indicates that Ezra Kramer authorized six illegal...
總統今天
The President convened
召開緊急內閣會議
an emergency cabinet meeting today
討論越來越多的
to discuss the growing scandal
政府涉嫌暗殺行動的醜聞
over an alleged government assassination program,
行動代號“黑荊棘”
code-named Blackbriar.
CIA局長愛茲拉•克雷莫因為授權此行動
CIA Director Ezra Kramer is under criminal investigation
受到司法調查
for authorizing the program,
其中幾起涉及到殺害美國公民
which in several cases may have even targeted US citizens.
兩個CIA的高級官員已被逮捕
Two agency officials have already been arrested.
阿爾伯特•赫斯醫生 “黑荊棘”計畫的策劃者
Dr. Albert Hirsch, the alleged mastermind of Blackbriar program
CIA部門長官諾亞•沃森 計畫實施的主管
and CIA Deputy Director Noah Vosen, the program's operational chief.
同時大衛•韋伯，或者說傑森•伯恩的下落
Meanwhile, mystery surrounds the fate of David Webb,
依然是個謎
also known as Jason Bourne, the source
他是揭露“黑荊棘”計畫的關鍵人物
behind the exposure of the Blackbriar program.
據報導韋伯被擊中，從曼哈頓的10樓屋頂
It's been reported that Webb was shot and fell from a Manhattan rooftop
墜入紐約東河
into the East River ten stories below.
但是經過三天的搜尋
However, after a three-day search,
韋伯的屍體仍然沒有被找到
Webb's body has yet to be found.